Jon Pugh

Brooklyn NY & Andover VT

ionpugh@live.com linkedin.com/in/jonpugh drupal.org/user/17028

Creative software engineer and entrepreneur with a focus on tools for more efficient development. Wishing to retire from Drupal in exchange for Symfony, Chef, Vagrant, Jekyll, Jenkins, and whatever the future may bring.

Actively working with HTML since 1997, CSS & Javascript since 1999, PHP/MySQL since 2000, exclusively using Drupal since 2004. Broad & deep understanding of all web technologies, front-end and back. Leading teams of developers since 2007.

Interested in open-source focused, results-driven workplaces that embrace internal entrepreneurship.

Open Source Projects

DEVSHOP

drupal.org/project/devshop

"Drupal DevOps in a Box". Git powered automation and workflow tools, with front and back end interfaces, multiple environments per project, and various tools to assist developers.

HUBDROP.IO

hubdrop.io

Mirrors drupal.org git repos on GitHub.com, using Symfony, Chef, & Jenkins.

DRUPAL CONTRIBUTIONS

- Two Drupal 8.x core commit credits.
- Many strange contrib modules, such as Features Orphans and Helpful.module.
- See drupal.org profile page for a full list of contributions.

Work Experience

THINKDROP CONSULTING

Founder & CEO January 2010 - Present

Launched and manages a successful boutique Drupal consultancy. Clients include Harvard Medical School, Institute for Integrative Nutrition, Sony Music, Lullabot, New Amsterdam Ideas,

Strawberry Frog, Bureau Blank, and numerous start-ups.

DRUPAL CONNECT

CTO June 2009 - January 2010

Managed entire consulting services branch of Drupal Staffing. Major projects included blogher.com andpbs.com/thisemotionallife.

FREELANCE

2004 - 2009

Major projects include ARIS (NYC Department of Education, Wireless Generation, WorkHabit), RaceForTheOceans.org (Oceana), and Sony Music artist websites.

TRELLON

Lead Developer October 2006 - September 2007

Lead development, assisted and trained junior developers on Drupal 4.7 and 5.0 projects. Major projects included Oceana, Rainforest Action Network, Blue Planet Run, the Columbia Spectator, The Red Cross, 247TownHall, and EndOil.org.

Volunteer Experience

MACILE/THINKDROP PILOT PROGRAM

Itabo, Dominican Republic July 2010

macile.org

Created and executed a week-long curriculum teaching the MACILE classes (age 12-17) about the internet, web pages, and web site creation. Over 5 days, for 2 hours a day, we were able to teach the basics of web site layout and organization, and create a class website using Drupal Gardens.

Formal Education

UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA

School of Fine Arts, Gainesville, Florida | 1999-2003

Studies in Digital Arts and Sciences

